Okay, so what we have seen just now is
that basically even the ideal processor
that can execute any number of
instructions per cycle still has to obey
raw dependencies meaning it still has to
wait for results to be produced before
they can be used by instructions that
need those results and uh that really
creates uh some of the delays that the
ideal processors are going to have and
that's why the ILP is not zero. it's
going to be something larger than zero
even for an ideal processor. So let us
now look at uh some instructions. So
let's say that I1 is producing a value
that is used by I2 and then I3 is
producing a value for I4 and then I4
produces a value that is used for I5. So
what is going to be the CPI for this
particular program?
Well, it's going to be CPI is equal how
many cycles do we need for these three
for these five instructions? Well,
here's what's going to happen. I1 can
execute immediately in the first cycle
and so can I3 because it doesn't have to
wait for anything. So, we spend one
cycle executing I1 and I3. The next
cycle, I2 can now go and I4 can also go
cuz I3 is now done. And then we still
need a third cycle to execute I5, which
has to wait for I4. So, we have spent
three cycles for five instructions,
which is going to be a CPI of 0.6. So
the CPI is still lower than one but uh
now it's even larger.
And finally if we did have this
dependence as well. Now we have to do I1
and then I2 and then I3 and then I4 and
then I5. So now the CPI with this is
going to be one. Why? Well, because we
need five cycles to execute five
instructions. So the CPI is going to be
one. So basically in the program the
dependencies the the raw dependencies
are going to determine basically what is
the possible CPI even if the processor
can do everything else ideally meaning
it can fetch any number of instructions.
It can decode and read registers in any
number of uh instructions but it simply
cannot provide time travel which uh
which uh we which is kind of the only
consideration that we really consider in
this case is just that you know we we
cannot do time travel. Everything else
we can do we still have a CPI that is
somewhere between one and zero. You
would have a CPI of zero if you have a
very large number of instructions with
no dependencies. We have seen that we
have a CPI of one. If you have any
number of instructions that are all
dependent on the previous instructions,
you really cannot do anything in
parallel.